

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Data Science Actuarial Science Risk Management Project Management

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python(Pandas, Scikit-learn, XGBoost, Shap, Dask, Plotly, Seaborn, Django, Sqlite...) AWS framework JupyterLab, Git, VS Code, PyCharm HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, React MongoDB, Mongoose SAS Office, VBA

PERSONAL SKILLS

Critical thinking Creativity Adaptability Communication Pragmatism Team Spirit

LANGUAGES

French (native) English (fluent) Italian (fluent)

CONTACT

Phone: +33 783440188 E-mail: paulrousset@hotmail.fr Linkedin

PAUL ROUSSET

DATA SCIENTIST

ABOUT

Actuary converted to Data Scientist, expert in data analysis, statistical modeling and machine learning techniques with Python. With a 13+ years professional experience (of which 7 in Italy), I am used to collaborate and communicate on technical projects with any type of stakeholders. Looking for a Data Scientist position with a forward-moving company

WORK EXPERIENCE

DATA SCIENTIST

Euler Hermes Italy - Milan |Oct 2018 - Dec 2021

- Development and maintenance of Machine Learning solutions (Credit Scoring, churn, propensity to purchase, loss prediction)
- Regional coordinator for data science projects (Mediterranean countries)
- Statistical analysis for business suport

ACTUARY / RISK MANAGER

Euler Hermes Italy - Rome | Sep 2014 - Sep 2018

- Implementation / improvements of Solvency II standards in MMEA Region
- Computation and reporting of Internal Model Parameters for EH Italy
- Pricing of Insurance products, statistical analysis, loss reserving

RISK MANAGER

Euler Hermes Group - Paris | Feb 2010 - Aug 2014

- Computation, reporting and analysis of the EH Group Solvency Ratio
- Group referent for Market Risk, Credit Risk and Reserve Risk
- Implementation of credit insurance model framework in several BUs
- Model validations with local regulators (France, Germany, Switzerland ...)

EDUCATION

MASTER DEGREE, ACTUARIAL AND FINANCIAL SCIENCES ISFA, Lyon | 2007 - 2009

BACHELOR OF SCIENCES, MATHEMATICS

Université Lyon 1 / University of Birmingham (UK) | 2006

CERTIFICATIONS

Web Developer Udemy, 2022

Applied Data Science with Python University of Michigan, 2018

Data Scientist in Python Dataquest.io, 2019